<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Ok That's Neat.]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.okthatsneat.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.okthatsneat.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-30T19:58:56+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.okthatsneat.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Philipp Hofmann]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.okthatsneat.com/blog/2013/08/30/setting-up-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-30T16:50:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.okthatsneat.com/blog/2013/08/30/setting-up-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>You are actually reading my first blog post ever.</h2>

<p>Kind of embarrassing, sure &ndash; but just like starting to write tests for your code (cough), never too late.
So why now? I&rsquo;m looking for a challenging new project (translates: I need a job), and besides making friends with 5 other programmers of your intended language / framework, starting a blog was the most common advise I came by. A good compilation of such advise was recently published by <a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/post/59405543569/giant-robots-podcast-episode-63-knowledge-bomb" title="Thoughtbot Podcast: knowledge bomb">Thoughtbot</a>.</p>

<p>Since I just spent 5 months hacking on a Ruby (on Rails) project, I chose the most popular blogging engine listed by <a href="https://www.ruby-toolbox.com/categories/Blog_Engines">Ruby Toolbox</a> &ndash; that site has never let me down.</p>

<p>Really, the most challenging part here was to come up with a &ldquo;creative&rdquo; domain name &ndash; I&rsquo;d really like to cloak the fact that I&rsquo;m a little new to this by not using the .herokuapp.com domain. Solution: phrase the general reaction you&rsquo;d want your readers to have when reading one of your posts. Feeling accomplished already!</p>

<p>After chipping out some virtual € to Godaddy, you get to click &ldquo;launch&rdquo; on your domain name, and edit the CNAME property of &ldquo;www&rdquo; to [your_heroku_app_name.herokuapp.com] in your DNS manager. I set TTL to half an hour, impatiently.</p>

<p>And of course I followed the getting started instructions over at <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/" title="Octopress setup">Octopress.com</a>.</p>

<p>This first post was then written inside Sublime Text 2 that keeps popping up a window asking my to buy it, and I think that&rsquo;s the only reason I haven&rsquo;t done so yet. But they do make an awesome IDE, featuring a <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/docs/2/spell_checking.html" title="Sublime Text 2 spellchecker">spell checker</a> that makes this post a little less bad. (edit: it sucks, it had no problemm with &ldquo;bogging&rdquo; but objects to &ldquo;blogging&rdquo; wtf)</p>

<p>I guess I&rsquo;ll have to get into the <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax" title="Markdown syntax">Markdown syntax</a> and the <a href="https://github.com/Shopify/liquid/wiki/Liquid-for-Designers" title="Liquid on Github">Liquid template language</a> now that I&rsquo;m blogging in it.</p>

<p>Oh, and of course to properly spy on you I also got myself a neat Google Analytics tracking ID that I configured Octopress with.
I&rsquo;ll dive into what that does If I&rsquo;m still interested in it tomorrow and report on my findings in another post.</p>

<p>Also up next: making this blog less ugly, and exploring everything that makes it look fancy to get me hired, preferably writing Ruby code.</p>

<p>Cheers!
-p</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
